- [Narrator] Eloquent includes
an inventing layer that
we can hook into to have
logic run when something
happens for each model instance.
Let's add some logic so that
when we create a new user,
it randomly assigns that user to a team.
To start, we'll be working in the User
model located in app, user.php.
We'll follow the same logic we did
before with a boot function.
This requires us to add a
boot method into our class.
Write on line 31 protected
static function boot()
As before, we're required
to call the parent method
with parent::boot() on line 33.
In this boot function we
can call a static method
named after the event we're
going to be interacting with.
In this case, it's the
creating method which is used,
obviously enough, when we're
creating a new model record.
The full list of events is provided
in the Laravel documentation.
These methods take a closure
with the model instance past.
So let's define the creating
method on line 34 with
static::creating(), and then
we'll pass in a closure with
function($model), and in
this method we can set the
model to set our team
ID value for the user to
a random value from the
database using, on line 35,
$model->team_id =
\DB::table('teams')->inRandomOrder(),
so we're selecting randomly
for that table, first()->id.
We'll verify that this works
by going to our application
and going to homestead.test/register.
We'll need to log out in this case.
Then go to register again,
and we'll sign up with a new account.
After we've registered and
logged into our account,
we can check our database
and look into the user's
table and verify that our
new user has a team_id set.